Tristan Moreland





(515) 451 5943



www.tristanmoreland.com

IT Leader with 10 years of application development experience delivering solutions based on organizational objectives. A proven track record of using my excellent personal, communication and organization skills to lead and improve application development teams, develop and recruit team members and improve team efficiencies.

Experience

Homesteaders Life Company, West Des Moines, Iowa

Director, Application Development/December 2019 - Present

- Lead a software delivery team of developers, quality assurance analysts, and business analysts with a focus on run and maintain activities
- Created a Report Developer role and team processes to more efficiently modify reports
- Introduced the organization to Microsoft Power BI dashboards by creating an executive, IT release communication and team metrics dashboard
- Brainstormed team service level agreement, resolution rate, and customer satisfaction metrics and set goals each year
- Led efforts to plan and on-board additional resources to ensure project completion by its due date
- Reduced team's backlog from 150+ items to less than 50
- Reduced after hour escalations from 30% to ~12%
- Improved overnight processing stability resulting in a 36% reduction in after-hours failures comparing 2020 vs. 2021

Run Team Manager/February 2019 – December 2019

- Developed and mentored a team of three software developers
- Delivered performance feedback to staff through individual meetings and annual performance reviews
- Implemented a customer satisfaction survey to better gauge customer sentiment
- Defined the process to hand off applications from project teams to the Run Team for support
- Led the effort to transition after hours support to an offshore company for tier 1 issues, eliminating the need for department wide on-call support
- Improved several team processes with automation and process mapping

United Suppliers/Land O'Lakes, Arden Hills, Minnesota

Senior Application Systems Developer 1/September 2017 – January 2019

- Sole developer on multi-tenancy order entry web application leveraging C# ASP.NET MVC and .NET Core
- Deployed web application to Azure Web App and Azure SQL
- Created data cleanup routine ran via Azure Function on a timer
- Project managed successful migration of 30+ applications between two data centers and domains
- Created and maintained project plan and timeline to keep application migration project on track
- Coordinated resources to complete pre-requisite tasks for each phase of the migration
- Learned and adopted ITIL change management, problem management and incident management

Senior Software Developer/October 2015 – September 2017

- Team lead and build manager for long term application re-write released December 2016
- Interviewed, on-boarded, and managed an intern for Summer 2017
- Experience with supervising and resource/capacity planning of two application development contractors
- Experience tracking and developing metrics to track project efficiency, throughput, and velocity

- Key role in implementing and documenting SDLC process improvements
- Documented and standardized development peer code review process and schedule
- Implemented continuous integration in our development stream, which lead to fewer broken builds
- Maintained/enhanced application architecture that utilizes MVVM to separate data and business rule layers
- Experience using Agile methodology and Kanban using JIRA for tracking issues and user stories

Software Developer/October 2014 – October 2015

- Led efforts in migration of Microsoft Dynamics/Great Plains 2013 custom application integrations
- Maintained/enhanced XML business to business integrations including but not limited to ship notice, order create, etc.
- Constructed SSIS packages to export data on a scheduled basis
- Leveraged DevExpress .Net controls (windows forms and ASP.net) to create an enhanced user experience

Junior Software Developer/May 2014 - October 2014

- Led efforts in migration of Microsoft Dynamics/Great Plains 2013 custom application integrations
- Maintained/enhanced XML business to business integrations including but not limited to ship notice, order create, etc.
- Constructed SSIS packages to export data on a scheduled basis
- Leveraged DevExpress .Net controls (windows forms and ASP.net) to create an enhanced user experience

Kreg Tool Company, Ankeny, Iowa

System Administrator & Programmer Analyst/May 2013 – May 2014

- Provided advanced technical support and resolved issues with ERP
- Attended multiple Kaizen events to optimize manufacturing processes
- Maintained 93% net promoter score from internal customers
- Managed and approved invoices from various external vendors
- Deployed and maintained Business Intelligence tools such as dashboards and analytics
- Created SQL stored procedures to make reporting more efficient
- Created custom reports that adhered to requirements gathered from users
- Standardized, consolidated, and optimized 150+ crystal reports
- Developed ad-hoc C#.net applications that integrated with a SQL database using best practices
- Optimized and tuned SQL queries, procedures, and views
- Experience with EDI processing and integration with SYSPRO ERP
- Developed, documented, and improved processes for end users
- Defined and documented MDI and KPI metrics
- Leveraged Automate 8 software to streamline repetitive workflow tasks

Report Developer/May 2012 - May 2013

- Created ad-hoc Crystal Reports per user specifications
- Migrated and standardized 15+ Microsoft Word reports to Crystal Reports for SYSPRO 6.1
- Assisted with ERP upgrade from SYSPRO 6.0 to 6.1
- SQL Scripting
- Transitioned all retail bar code labels from Loftware to Bartender

Technologies

Visual Studio • Visual Studio Code • SQL Server 2008 R2 • SSRS • SSIS • Crystal Reports (Version 8.5 • 10.2 • 2008 • 2013) • Perforce Source Control • Perforce Swarm • VSTS • GIT • JIRA • Confluence • Jenkins • Azure Web Apps • Azure SQL • Azure Functions • JAMS Automation • Azure DevOps • Azure Boards • PowerBI • JAMS Scheduler • C# • VB.NET • ASP.NET MVC • .NET Core • VB6 • SQL • PowerShell Scripting • Batch Scripting • DevExpress Controls

Education

B. S. Management Information Systems/Iowa State University, Ames, Iowa – May 2013

A.A.S Electronic Engineering/Des Moines Area Community College, Ankeny, Iowa – May 2007